https://teach.starfall.com/lv/info/privacy

Starfall.com
Starfall Store
Starfall Updates
Need Help?
Starfall Updates
Need Help?
Privacy Policy
Last Updated: 5 May 2020
Starfall Education Foundation (“we”) strives to create a safe and playful environment for all children. Throughout our services (collectively “services”) — the many Starfall Apps for mobile devices, the Starfall website for children (www.starfall.com), the Starfall Parent-Teacher Center™ (teach.starfall.com), and the Starfall Store™ (store.starfall.com) — we adhere to a strict policy of respecting and protecting the privacy of our users.
Starfall does not collect personal information from children or track children's progress. Children do not provide personal information to access and use our services. The Starfall websites and apps directed toward children operate in accordance with COPPA and FERPA. Starfall does not display any advertising to children.
Starfall.com is listed by the kidSAFE Seal Program. To learn more, go to www.kidsafeseal.com.
Personal Information Collection and Use
We ask adult users (“you”) to provide information about themselves when logging in to the member portion of Starfall or when completing a purchase in our store. We do not ask for or collect information from children.
Basic Membership Information: When you become a member of Starfall, you must provide general personal information such as your name, email address, and a password. We may again ask for this information when you login or when you make changes to your account.
Payment Information: When you make a purchase, whether it is for an online membership or a physical product, we require billing and shipping information. This sensitive information is handled with the utmost care. We send payment information to a secure and nationally recognized payment processor using strong industry standard encryption. Once a purchase has been made we do not store credit card numbers, nor do we have access to credit card numbers through our payment processor. In order to provide customer service, we retain the details of a purchase, such as the payment date, the billing address, and the shipping address.
Use of Information: We use the information we collect to operate, maintain and enhance the services we provide, as well as to communicate with you about your account or from time to time to send you emails about services or activities that may be of interest to you.
Third Parties: We do not rent or sell your personal information to third parties. We do share or disclose your personal information with our trusted vendors, but only as needed to provide our services. These vendor services may include hosting, email delivery, and payment services.
Technical Information Collection and Use
When you use Starfall on a computer or mobile device, we collect some basic technical information in order to customize your experience as well as to improve our services.
Cookies: Like many websites, we rely on cookies (a small text file sent to your browser) to give us a better understanding of how many unique users we have and how they are using our site. We also use cookies to retain your preferences and remember the state of an activity such as an online shopping cart or service such as a membership login. We do not collect personal information through cookies.
Other Information: We automatically receive and record information on our server logs from a user’s browser, including a user’s IP address. We may collect information about the browser, operating system, or mobile device being used, as well as information about geographic locations and patterns of usage. We keep these records so that we can analyze the 'big picture' of how our visitors use our site and to analyze any technical problems that could occur.
Use of Information: We use the information collected to deliver content, support, track and enhance a user’s experience of our services. For example, when a user returns to the services after logging in, cookies help us recognize that user without having to log back in. Additionally, by understanding usage trends, behaviors and preferences of our users, we can improve our services and develop new features and functionality.
Updating Information and Disclosure of Information
Please contact us at helpdesk@starfall.com to update or delete your personal information. We may not be able to delete information in all instances, such as information retained in technical support logs and other business records.
Starfall may disclose information we have retained if we believe it necessary to comply with a legal process, law enforcement investigation, or government request. We may also divulge collected information in response to fraud or technical security issues or in matters of public safety. Any such disclosure will be tailored to disclose only the specifically requested information to the requesting authority.
International Visitors and Use Outside the U.S.
Our services are operated and managed on servers located within the United States. If you are using our services outside the United States, you consent to having your information and data transferred to the United States for the purpose of performing the services according to our Terms of Service. If you are in any jurisdiction with laws or regulations governing internet use, including collection, use, and disclosure of personal data, different from those of the United States, you may only use our services in a manner that is lawful in your jurisdiction. Please do not use our services if use of our services is unlawful in your jurisdiction.
This paragraph outlines our compliance with the General Data and Protection Regulation (GDPR) of the European Union and other applicable data protection laws. Starfall is the company that controls your data and is sometimes called the ‘data controller’ within the terms of the GDPR. We maintain records of all requests and our responses with respect to issues addressed in this Privacy Policy. Under the GDPR, we must maintain a data inventory and data flow mapping for compliance purposes.
You have various rights under data protection laws and you have the right, without charge, upon verification of identity, to:
Request a copy of the personal information about you that we have
Correct any inaccuracies in personal data about you that we have
Withdraw your consent where we have requested your consent to process information
Delete personal information within legally prescribed limitations
Lodge a complaint with the appropriate public authority if you have any concerns about how we process or retain your data
If you have any questions or requests concerning these rights, please contact us at helpdesk@starfall.com and your inquiry will be responded to as soon as possible but within 30 days of our receipt of your request.
We have appointed an internal Data Protection Officer for you to contact if you have any questions regarding our privacy policy or if you wish to exercise your data protection rights. Your first point of contact should be with our customer service team that can be contacted at helpdesk@starfall.com. The Data Protection Officer for residents of the European Union may be contacted at euprivacy@starfall.com.
COPPA and FERPA
We do not collect personal information from children or track children's progress. Children do not provide personal information to use and access our services. The Starfall websites and apps directed toward children operate in accordance and are consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).
Security
Our servers are located in a secured, locked, and monitored environment. Data access is controlled by several firewall layers. Since no system is absolutely fail proof, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information. However, we employ physical, technical and administrative security measures designed to safeguard user information that follow or exceed industry standards.
Advertising and Social Media
Starfall does not display any advertising to children on our websites or apps. We strongly believe that children should not be the targets of marketing efforts during their educational experience. Resources for grown-ups, specifically those found on the Starfall Parent-Teacher Center™ and the Starfall Store™, may contain links to social media services, but are kept separate from children's activities and safeguarded behind a parent gate.
Updates
We may make changes to this privacy policy from time to time and will notify you of changes by posting the revised privacy policy with an updated date of revision on our websites. If we change this privacy policy in a material manner, we will do our best to notify you of the changes by posting a notice on our websites. Your continued use of our services following the effective date of such update constitutes your acceptance of the revised policy.
Contact Information
Please contact Starfall with any questions or comments.
By email: helpdesk@starfall.com
By mail: Starfall Education Foundation, PO Box 359, Boulder, CO 80306
About Starfall
Contact Us
Privacy Policy
Terms of Service
Accessibility
The Starfall Parent-Teacher Center™ is a program service of Starfall Education Foundation, a publicly supported nonprofit organization, 501(c)(3). Starfall® and Starfall.com® are registered trademarks in the U.S., the European Union, and various other countries. Copyright © 2002–2020 by Starfall Education. All rights reserved.
We permit materials from the Starfall Parent-Teacher Center™ to be reproduced by teachers or parents for noncommercial use in their classroom or home. Any other reproduction is prohibited without written permission from the publisher.
Parent-Teacher Center v 3.4.2.0
